Finding aid for the John Fante papers LSC.1832
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 2. Correspondences, 1932-1998
  - 1. John Fante Correspondences, 1932-1998
    - C-I, 1935-1981 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      163 items
    - Campiglia, Josephine, 1932-1952 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      12 items
    - Covici, Pascal, 1937-1963 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      128 items
    - DeLaurentiis, Dino, 1957-1965 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Fan Letters 1 of 2, 1934-1981 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      51 items
    - Fan Letters 2 of 2, 1982-1997 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      42 items
    - Fante, Joyce and children, 1938-1960 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      63 items
    - Fante, Mary, Nick, and Tom 1 of 3, 1932-1934 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      77 items
    - Fante, Mary, Nick, and Tom 2 of 3, 1935-1940 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Fante, Mary, Nick, and Tom 3 of 3, 1941-1980 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      67 items
    - J-M, 1932-1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      118 items
    - McIntosh & Otis Inc., 1939-1978 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      91 items
    - McWilliams, Carey, 1933-1981 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      35 items
    - Mencken, H. L., 1930-1952 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      43 items
    - N-S, 1936-1980 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      120 items
    - Saroyan, William, 1935-1959 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      26 items
    - Stackpole Sons Publishers, 1938-1951 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      40 items
    - T-Z, 1932-1978 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - 2. Joyce Fante Correspondences, 1978-1999
    - A, 1983-1992 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      46 items
    - B, 1983-1996 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      54 items
    - Black Sparrow Press 1 of 2, 1979-1986 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      141 items
    - Black Sparrow Press 2 of 2, 1987-1999 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      234 items
    - C-F, 1983-1995 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      72 items
    - G-H, 1984-1998 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      75 items
    - I-Mc, 1978-1997 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Md-Mz, 1983-1993 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      50 items
    - N-P, 1982-1993 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Q-S, 1983-1997 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      112 items
    - The Stanford University Libraries, 1989-1995 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      49 items
    - T-Z, 1983-1987 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      31 items
- 3. Writings by Others, 1938-1999
  Contains screenplays, clippings, magazines, newspapers and other materials related and unrelated to John Fante.
  - 1. Writings by Others regarding John Fante, 1938-1999
    - A-B, 1957-1992 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      16 items
    - C, 1975-1995 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Casella, Max "The Long Winter" screenplay, 1995 October 9 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Cooper, Stephen "Full of Life" 1 of 3, No Date (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Cooper, Stephen "Full of Life" 2 of 3, No Date (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Cooper, Stephen "Full of Life" 3 of 3, No Date (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - D-E, 1975-1995 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      25 items
    - Deruddere, Dominique "Wait Until Spring, Bandini" screenplay, 1987 August (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Deruddere, Dominique "Wait Until Spring, Bandini" screenplay, 1988 September (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Domercq, Bruno "Passions: Accordez-lui cette valse", 1989 November (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Domercq, Bruno "Passions: Accordez-lui cette valse", 1989 November (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - F, 1983-1993 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - French articles and reviews, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Fante, Joyce miscellaneous writings, ca. 1994 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - G, 1980-1995 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      20 items
    - H, 1940-1991 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Hanson, Curtis "The Brotherhood of the Grape" screenplay, no date (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Hertoghs, Jan "This boy made his way out of a deep dark hole" television treatment, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Hirsch, Mikael "Fathers and Sons on the Move in John Fante" master's thesis, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - I-L, 1975-1989 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      14 items
    - Jenkins, Victoria "1933 Was a Bad Year" screenplay, 1988 September (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - M, 1975-1999 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      21 items
    - Mathison, Melissa and Claude Berri "My Dog Stupid" screenplay, 1988 October (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Moreau, Michael "John Fante and H. L. Mencken a Personal Correspondence 1930-1952" manuscript 1 of 2, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Moreau, Michael "John Fante and H. L. Mencken a Personal Correspondence 1930-1952" manuscript 2 of 2, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - N-O, 1952-1993 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - O'Flaherty, Dennis "Brotherhood of the Grape" screenplay, no date (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - P-R, 1938-1994 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Russo, Richard "A Wife for Dino Rossi" screenplay, no date (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - S-Z, 1940-1991 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      37 items
    - See, Carolyn "When Sin Was Still Fun on Hollywood Boulevard" article, 1977 October (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Shacochis, Bob "Forgotten Son of the Lost Generation" article 1 of 2, 1987 December (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Shacochis, Bob "Forgotten Son of the Lost Generation" article 2 of 2, 1987 December (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Tolkin, Stephen "Ask the Dust" screenplay, 1989 March 10 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Tolkin, Stephen "Ask the Dust" screenplay, no date (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Towne, Robert "The Brotherhood of the Grape" fragment of screenplay, 1991 November 7 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Towne, Robert "Ask the Dust" screenplay, 1992, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Towne, Robert "Ask the Dust" screenplay, 1993 March 30 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Whitney, Mary "Fantes Across America" book, 1990 April 4 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Wright, Gilbert "Maya the Magnificent" screenplay, no date (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Miscellany, no dates (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Vittorini, Elio "Americana" anthology, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Farrell, Edmund J. "I/You - We/They" anthology, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Mayer, Karl H. and Barbara Pohl "Warten auf Wunder" book 1 of 2, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Mayer, Karl H. and Barbara Pohl "Warten auf Wunder" book 2 of 2, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Kordich, Catherine J. "John Fante's Kaleidoscopic Los Angeles" master's thesis, 1994 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - A-C, ca. 1940-1990 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - D, 1941-1991 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      10 items
    - E-G, 1985-1995 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - H-N, 1940-1991 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - O-P, 1979-1990 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      8 items
    - Q-R, 1986-1994 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      11 items
    - S-Z and Miscellany, 1957-1995 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - 2. Writings by Others Assorted, 1941-1991
    - A-H, 1941-1989 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Bode, William T. "An Incident of Love" teleplay, 1956 July 23 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Borchert, Rudolph "Trotsky" screenplay, no date (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Borchert, Rudolph "Walker Colt" screenplay, no date (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Bukowski, Charles "The Rats of Thirst" screenplay, no date (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Capote, Truman "House of Flowers" musical play, no date (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Coppola, Francis F. clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Dever, Joseph "Three Priests" synopsis, 1958 May 15 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Dunn, Geoffrey "Dollar a day, 10? a dance" broadside and "Santa Cruz is in the Heart" book, 1985 and 1989 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Englund, Ken "Tubie's Monument" screenplay, 1958 March 3 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Fenton, Frank collection of poems, no date (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Ferguson, Graham "Il Fatto Della Vita" treatment, no date (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Griffin, Eleanore "Next Time We Love" screenplay, 1961 June 21 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Hier, Grant "Bastard Alibis and Alabaster Lies" collection of poems 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Hier, Grant "Bastard Alibis and Alabaster Lies" collection of poems 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Hier, Grant "Bastard Alibis and Alabaster Lies" collection of poems 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Hier, Grant "Bastard Alibis and Alabaster Lies" collection of poems 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - I-P, 1978-1994 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      28 items
    - Leonard, Jack "Whipsaw" script, 1952 December 4 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Leonard, Jack and Lawrence Resner "No Place to Die" screenplay, no date (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Monte "Take Hold on Folly" manuscript, no date (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Q-T, 1952-1990 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      17 items
    - Sonego, Rudolfo "An Italian in America" manuscript, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Stanley, Jackson "The Man who was Irresistible to Women" teleplay, no date (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - U-Z, 1941-1987 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Winnikoff, Albert and Burt Prelutsky "Sell, Sell, Sell" manuscript, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Miscellany, ca. 1950s-1980s (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - McWilliams, Carey "Witch Hunt: The Revival of Heresy" book, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Essex, Harry "Man and Boy" book, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Hylen, Arnold "Bunker Hill: A Los Angeles Landmark" book, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - A-Z and Miscellany, 1942-1991 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      52 items
    - Goldman, Stuart clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      27 items
- 4. Associated Events, 1956-1995
  This series contains promotional items and other materials about events related to Fante?s work. These events include films, theatrical productions, exhibitions, screenings and conferences. Items are arranged chronologically.
  - "Full of Life" film, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - "The Saga of Arturo Bandini" theatrical production, ca. early 1980s (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Western Books Exhibition, 1981, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" theatrical production, 1984 June-July (Box 54, Folder 4)
    38 items
  - "Colorado Inspired" exhibition, 1986 December 5- 1987 March 15 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - "Wait Until Spring, Bandini" film, ca. 1989-1990 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - "The Reluctant Saint" screening, 1994 May 25 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - "John Fante: The First Conference", 1995 May 4-6 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    22 items
- 5. Financial Records, 1933-1998
  This series contains contracts, checks, receipts, residual statements, income tax records and other materials related to Fante?s professional and personal financial records.
  - 1. Professional Records, 1933-1998
    - A-C, 1933-1985 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Columbia Pictures "Full of Life", 1956-1970 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - D-H, 1935-1998 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - I-M, 1935-1980 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, 1952 July 30 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - N-Z, 1934-1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Security Pictures Inc., 1950-1985 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Twentieth Century Fox, 1950-1959 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Writers Guild of America Pension Plan, 1957-1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Writers Guild of America, West Federal Credit Union, 1956-1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Writers Guild of America, West Insurance, 1958-1978 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Writers Guild of America, West Residual Statements, 1966-1985 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Writers Guild of America Miscellany, 1956-1983 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - 2. Income Tax and Personal Expense Records, 1939-1991
    - A-Ce, 1945-1990 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Cf-K, 1951-1977 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - L-St, 1939-1985 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Su-Z, 1940-1978 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1942-1949 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1951-1963 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1964-1971 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1966-1977 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1978-1981 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1984-1986 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Income Tax Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Income Tax Notes, ca. early 1960s (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Income Tax Notes, 1962-1968 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Income Tax Notes, 1969-1973 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Income Tax Notes, 1974-1978 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1944-1953 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1955-1956 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1957 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1958-1959 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1960-1962 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1965-1968 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1969-1973 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Personal Expense Records, 1974-1977 (Box 48, Folder 2)
- 6. Personal Records and Materials, 1925-2000
  This series contains Fante?s personal materials and miscellaneous items from the collection. The series has been arranged alphabetically.
  - A-E, 1931-1995 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Diaries, 1933-1951 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - F-Q, 1954-1996 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Fante, Mary, 1943-1980 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - R, 1926-1978 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - S-Z, 1954-2000 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - High School Scrapbook, probably 1925 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook A, 1933-1962 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" Scrapbook, 1940-1977 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook B, 1983-1989 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook C, 1989-1990 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Miscellany, 1944-1984 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - "Charles Bukowski, Hello. It's good to be back" (Box 54, Folder 9)
    Scope and Content
    33 1/3 LP. Signed to John Fante by Hank Charles Bukowski.
  - Typewriter, no date (Box 55, Folder 1)